Nelson C. Nye papers, 1941-1988
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Nelson C. Nye manuscripts, 1941-1988
AZ 332
This is a collection of 24 published manuscripts with holograph corrections, chiefly published in the 1960s.
Nye, Nelson C. (Nelson Coral), 1907-1997
2.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Nelson C. Nye was a Western writer originally from Chicago, Illinois. He worked as a ranch hand in Texas before owning a horse ranch in New Mexico. He studied under authors Laurence D'Orsay and Arthur Sullivant and wrote numerous Westerns under his own name and pseudonyms Drake Denver and Clem Colt. In addition, Nye was one of the founders and twice served as president of Western Writers of America.
Scope and Content Note
This is a collection of 24 published manuscripts with holograph corrections, chiefly published in the 1960s
Access Terms
Nye, Nelson C. (Nelson Coral), 1907-1997 -- Manuscripts
Manuscripts, American
Western stories
Manuscripts
Container List
- Undated manuscript of Complete Book of the Quarter Horse. Published by A. S. Barnes, New York, 1964. No date (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Undated manuscript of Champions of the Quarter Tracks. Published by Coward-McCann, New York, 1950. No date (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Undated manuscript of Curly Bill Story. Published as The Seven Six-Gunners by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1963. No date (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Published in England by Collins as Death Comes Riding, 1962.
- Undated manuscript of The Irreverent Scout. Published by Mills & Boon, Inc., England, 1961. No date (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Published as Frontier Scout by Vega Books, Inc., New York, 1964.
- Undated manuscript of Pistols for Hire. Published by Macmillan, New York, 1941. No date (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Later published as A Bullet for Billy the Kid.
- Undated manuscript of Treasure Trail from Tucson. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1964 in volume with Sudden Country. No date (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Undated manuscript of Trail of Lost Skulls. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1967. No date (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Undated manuscript of Ambush at Yuma's Chimney. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1965. No date (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Undated manuscript of Gun Feud at Tiedown. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1965. No date (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Undated manuscript of A Lost Mine Named Salvation. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1968. No date (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Undated manuscript of Not Grass Alone. Published by Macmillan, New York, 1961. No date (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Undated manuscript of Rider on the Roan. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1967. No date (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Undated manuscript of Iron Hand. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1966. No date (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Undated manuscript of The Marshall of Pioche. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1966. No date (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Undated manuscript of Rogue's Rendezvous. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1965. No date (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Undated manuscript of Single Action. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1967. No date (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Undated manuscript of Sudden Country. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1964. No date (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Undated manuscript of Wolftrap. Published by Ace Books, Inc., New York, 1969. No date (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Undated manuscript of Trigger Talk. Published by Phoenix Press, 1942. No date (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Undated manuscript of Gringo. Published by Ace Books, 1969. No date (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Undated manuscript of Trouble at Pena Blanca. Published by Avon Books, 1969. No date (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
- Undated manuscript of Hellhound for Ballarat. Published by Ace Books, 1970. No date (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Readers proofs of Mule Man. Published by Doubleday, 1988. No date (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  Includes a carbon copy of the original typescript.
- Undated manuscript of No Place to Hide Published by Paper Jacks, 1988. No date (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  Originally titled Heir to Bullybueno. Includes pages 1-113 of the original typescript and photocopies of pages 114-169.